Sahil SHARMA

www.coderfoundry.com/sahilsharma

FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML5
CSS3
JavaScript/ES6
JQuery
Bootstrap
.NET
C#
MVC
ASP.NET
SQL & Bash
LINQ
Xamarin
WebAPI

C

C++

CODER FOUNDRY

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284 (336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

EDUCATION

Guru Nanak Dev University, Bachelor of Computer Applications *Amritsar, India · 2012*

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Coder Foundry, Web Software Engineer

Kernersville, NC · January 2020–March 2020

- Created three primary projects, including:
 - 1. A portfolio site using C#, MVC, HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP, JS & jQuery.
 - 2. A Financial Portal implemented in three phases. Phase 1: an MVC Web Application, Phase 2: a Web Service that utilizes Swagger and Swashbuckle for integrated testing, Phase 3: A cross platform Xamarin Mobile Application.
 - 3. Fully designed and developed a multi-functional issue tracker web application, implementing enhanced roles & security, which also used a Code First Relational database designed and modeled in SQL Server. Technologies used include: .Net Framework v. 4.6.1, MVC5, C#, LINQ, SQL, Entity Framework, jQuery DataTables.

Shivaan Inc DBA Kwik JP Express, Cashier

Greensboro, NC · October 2018–September 2019

- Operated Ruby2 cash register to manage cash, credit and debit card transactions.
- Adhered to all city, state and federal tobacco and alcohol regulations.
- Performed record and bookkeeping at the end of the shift.
- Executed inventory and stocking of goods and merchandise inside the store.
- Experience with: 10-key calculators, lottery machines, Credit card readers, Desktop computers, Gas pump controllers, handheld bar code scanners

Government of India, Military Engineer Services

Kapurthala, India · June 2010–July 2018

- Employee payroll preparation
- Preparing budget estimates keeping in view the progress of ongoing defense projects and submission to senior management.
- Preparation and auditing of monthly expenditure reports and submission to higher authorities.
- Creation and disbursement of To Do task schedules to fellow employees.
- Keep track of the progress of ongoing defense mechanical, electrical and civil engineering projects and ensure timely completion.